<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Recipes]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib\media\favicon.png</url><title>Recipes</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 12:13:45 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib\rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 12:13:43 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[Butterscotch Sauce]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>4oz Butter
<br>4oz Soft Dark Brown Sugar
<br>300 ml Double Cream
<br>Vanilla Essence
<br><br>Melt the butter and sugar together until fully melted and combined.<br>
Add the cream and stir until fully combined and sauce is a light golden colour]]></description><link>components\butterscotch-sauce.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Components/Butterscotch Sauce.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 18:02:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Components]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 ]]></description><link>components\components.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Components/Components.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 12:09:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Confit Duck]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>6 Duck Legs (Optionally Trimmed)
<br>Duck Fat
<br>1 Orange
<br>Fresh Thyme
<br>4 Cloves of Garlic
<br>100 g Sea Salt
<br><br>Start by juicing and zesting the orange into a bowl, roughly chop some thyme and crush the garlic then combine with orange add to the salt. The mix should make a kind of paste. Rub this all over the duck legs and arrange them in a single layer on a tray. Use all the salt and just kind of pack it all over. If you need more, then just make up some more mix.<br>Put in the fridge for about 24 hours.<br>After 24 hours rinse the salt from the duck legs under running cold water, pat dry and place in a baking tray deep enough that the duck legs can be completely covered.<br>Cover the duck legs in duck fat and cook in a low oven (about 120o) for about 4 hours. The legs should be cooked through and very tender. Place the duck legs in a storage container and strain the duck fat over them so they are fully submerged (The straining is just to remove any impurities from the fat). Allow them to cool in the fat.<br>They will keep in the fridge for several weeks. The salting acts as a preservative and storing them fully submerged in the fat seals them.<br>When you want to eat them just take them out of the fat and heat through. You can either place them on a dry pan/baking sheet and warm in a hot oven, or to ensure a nice crispy skin drop them into a hot (clean) fryer for a minute or two first.]]></description><link>components\confit-duck.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Components/Confit Duck.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 18:02:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Crème Patisserie]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>6 egg yolks
<br>125g caster sugar
<br>Vanilla Essence (A couple of drops depending on brand)
<br>60 g plain flour
<br>500ml butter
<br>15g salted butter
]]></description><link>components\crème-patisserie.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Components/Crème Patisserie.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 18:02:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Italian Meringue]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>500g Caster Sugar
<br>Water
<br>8 Egg Whites
<br><br>Put the sugar in a pan with just enough water to cover it, and heat to 140­o C (Use a sugar thermometer)<br>While the syrup is heating put the egg whites in a clean metal bowl and whisk till stiff peaks form.<br>Once the syrup is at temperature slowly pour into the egg whites while continuing to whisk them, the heat from the syrup will cook the egg whites so no further cooking will be necessary. Once all the syrup is in the egg whites, continue whisking until the meringue has cooled. It should have a mallow texture to it.<br>You can now pipe it onto pies or flans or anything else you like, and you can use a blowtorch to colour the piped meringue. If you don't have a blowtorch just place under a hot grill for a few seconds.]]></description><link>components\italian-meringue.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Components/Italian Meringue.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 18:02:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Orange and Balsamic Dressing]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>1 ltr Balsamic Vinegar
<br>1 ltr Orange Juice
<br>100 g Caster Sugar
<br><br>Place all the ingredients in a stainless-steel pan and reduce to a syrup.]]></description><link>components\orange-and-balsamic-dressing.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Components/Orange and Balsamic Dressing.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 18:02:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Lunches]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 ]]></description><link>lunches\lunches.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Lunches/Lunches.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 12:08:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mains]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 ]]></description><link>mains\mains.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Mains/Mains.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 12:09:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Odds & Sods]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 ]]></description><link>odds-&amp;-sods\odds-&amp;-sods.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Odds &amp; Sods/Odds &amp; Sods.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 12:09:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cranachan]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>Double Cream
<br>Rolled Oats
<br>Honey
<br>Drambui (or Glayva, or just Whisky)
<br>Fresh Raspberries
<br><br>Toast the oats either in a dry pan or under a grill (they will burn very quickly so don't look away)<br>
Add a good slug if the alcohol to the cream and then whisk to soft peaks, gently fold through the honey, toasted oats and raspberries.<br><br>You can make a coulis with some of teh rapsberries and drizzle it over as well.]]></description><link>puddings\cranachan.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Puddings/Cranachan.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 18:15:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pavlova]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br><br>
<br>12 Egg Whites
<br>1 ½ lb Caster Sugar
<br>1 tsp Cornflour
<br>1 tsp Vinegar
<br><br>
<br>Double Cream
<br>Vanilla Essence/Vanilla Paste
<br>Fruit (Fresh berries such as raspberries or brambles are good)
<br><br>Put the egg whites in a stainless-steel bowl and whisk until fluffy, add sugar, cornflour and vinegar and continue whisking until glossy.<br>Spread on a tray or pipe into nests.<br>Bake at 120 degrees Celsius for a couple of hours, then turn the oven off and leave the meringue in to cool. The Meringue should be crisp and crumbly on the outside with a slightly mallowy centre.<br>Whip the cream with a touch of vanilla added to taste until stiff. Top the cooled meringue with the cream and whatever fruit you like.]]></description><link>puddings\pavlova.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Puddings/Pavlova.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 18:03:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Puddings]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 ]]></description><link>puddings\puddings.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Puddings/Puddings.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 12:08:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Chocolate "Mousse"]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>Crème Patisserie
<br>Double Cream
<br>Chocolate
<br><br>Whip the double cream to medium/firm peaks, then fold through the Crème Patisserie until well combined.<br>
Then fold through melted chocolate until well combined.<br>
Chill.]]></description><link>puddings\simple.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Puddings/Simple.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 18:20:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sticky Toffee Pudding]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>12oz Dates
<br>1pt Water
<br>1tsp Bicarbonate of Soda
<br>4oz Butter
<br>12oz Soft Brown Sugar
<br>4 Eggs
<br>120z Plain Flour
<br>1 tbsp Baking Powder
<br><br>Sift the flour and baking powder together.<br>In a bowl cream the butter and sugar, then add the eggs one at a time with some of the sifted flour, waiting till it's all incorporated before adding the next. Once all the eggs are in, add the rest of the flour and mix till smooth.<br>Put dates, and water in a pan and bring to the boil. Once boiling at the bicarb then add to the rest of the mix. Stir well then put in a lined loaf tin, and in the oven for about 45 minutes.]]></description><link>puddings\sticky-toffee-pudding.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Puddings/Sticky Toffee Pudding.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 18:03:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA["Roast" Potatoes]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>Good Floury Potatoes (Maris Piper/ Cyprus etc)
<br><br>Peel and par-boil the potatoes an salted water.<br>Drain into a colander and give a good shake to rough up the edges.<br>Finish in a deep fat fryer at 180/190 degrees.]]></description><link>sides\roast-potatoes.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Sides/Roast Potatoes.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 18:03:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sides]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 ]]></description><link>sides\sides.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Sides/Sides.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 12:09:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Yorkshire Puddings]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>Eggs
<br>Milk
<br>Plain Flour
<br>Salt/Pepper
<br><br>Break the eggs into a measuring jug and note the volume, transfer to a mixing bowl and then measure the same volume of milk and then the same volume of flour. Beat all 3 together along with salt and pepper and store in a jug This can be done several hours in advance.<br>Heat an oven to 200 degrees Celsius.<br>Place a good amount of oil in each section of a Yorkshire pudding tin. Place the tray in the oven until the oil is very, very hot (almost smoking).<br>Pour your mixture into the tins and place back in oven until ready. The oil should be hot enough that the edges start setting the moment you pour the mixture into the tin. If it isn't then heat the oil up more before proceeding.]]></description><link>sides\yorkshire-pudding.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Sides/Yorkshire Pudding.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 18:03:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Shortbread]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>3 Cups Plain Flour (Sifted) (12oz)
<br>1 Cup Icing Sugar (4 oz)
<br>1 Cup Cornflour (this can be replaced with oatmeal (not porridge oats) for a slightly different texture and nuttier flavour) (4 oz)
<br>1 ½ Blocks Cold Butter (12 oz)
<br><br>Chop butter and put in food processor with icing sugar, pulse until it looks like millions. Add both flours and pulse until it looks like breadcrumbs. Empty onto cold surface and knead lightly till it comes into a solid paste. Chill.<br>Roll thinly and cut into rounds. Place on baking sheet and put in oven until just starting to colour. Place on cooling rack and while still hot from the oven sprinkle caster sugar over the top.]]></description><link>snacks\shortbread.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Snacks/Shortbread.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 18:04:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Snacks]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 ]]></description><link>snacks\snacks.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Snacks/Snacks.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 12:09:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tablet]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>125g butter, plus extra to grease
<br>1kg golden sugar (granulated or caster)
<br>½ tsp salt
<br>250ml whole milk
<br>350ml condensed milk
<br>½ tsp vanilla extract (optional)
<br><br>Grease a shallow tin approximately 25cm x 35cm. Melt the butter in a large, heavy-based pan (as tall as you have) over a low heat. Add the sugar, salt and milk and stir until the sugar has dissolved. Bring to the boil and simmer over a fairly high heat for eight minutes.<br>Add the condensed milk, stir well, then turn the heat down and let it simmer for about another 15 minutes, stirring occasionally. Start testing at this point: once it reaches 115C, it's done. (Alternatively, dribble some of the mixture on to a cold saucer. Leave for a couple of minutes, then push it with your finger; if it sets, it's done.)<br>Take off the heat, add any flavourings, if using, and beat vigorously with a wooden spoon or electric beaters until thickened but still pourable (about 10 minutes if done manually, less with beaters). Pour into the prepared tin and leave to set, scoring squares after about 20 minutes. It is best left out to dry slightly overnight.]]></description><link>snacks\tablet.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Snacks/Tablet.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 18:04:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Confit Duck with Tomato and Parmesan Salad]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>4 x <a data-href="Confit Duck" href="\components\confit-duck.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Confit Duck</a> legs
<br>4 Large Tomatoes
<br>1 Small Red Onion
<br>Parmesan
<br>Salt/Pepper
<br><a data-href="Orange and Balsamic Dressing" href="\components\orange-and-balsamic-dressing.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Orange and Balsamic Dressing</a>
<br><br>Crisp up the Duck Legs by either placing in a hot oven for 15 minutes, or dropping in a clean fryer.<br>Half the tomatoes vertically then slice each half horizontally as thinly as you can, peel the onion and halve vertically, then thinly slice it vertically, toss the sliced tomato, sliced onion and parmesan, seasoning to taste with salt and pepper.<br>Split the salad between 4 plates, place the crisped confit legs on top and drizzle with the dressing.]]></description><link>starters\meat\confit-duck-with-tomato-and-parmesan-salad.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Starters/Meat/Confit Duck With Tomato and Parmesan Salad.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 18:04:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cream of (Random Vegetable) Soup]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>Onions
<br>1 Type of random vegetable
<br>Butter
<br>Cream
<br>Seasoning
<br><br>Chop the onions and vegetables.<br>Heat a thick bottomed pan and then add a knob of butter. Add the chopped onions and vegetables and lightly season, sweat the onions and veg till they start to cook through, add just enough water to cover and no more and continue cooking until the veg is cooked through. Blitz the soup until smooth and press through a sieve or chinois (this bit can be missed if you don't care too much about bits), put back on the heat and add cream and check seasoning.<br><br>If you are using good veg you really shouldn't need to use stock to add flavour, but if you find your soups to be a bit bland then feel free to use a light chicken or vegetable stock instead of the water.<br>You can also use combinations of veg, obvious ones would be Leek and Potato (chill it and call it Vichyssoise) or carrot and parsnip (add some ground spice for a spiced version).]]></description><link>starters\soups\cream-of-veg.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Starters/Soups/Cream of Veg.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 18:04:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cullen Skink]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>Smoked Haddock
<br>Finely Chopped Onions
<br>Diced Peeled Potatoes
<br>Chicken Bouillon/Cube
<br>Cream
<br>Butter
<br>Seasoning
<br><br>This recipe doesn't have any exact quantities and can be scaled to whatever amount you need.<br>You need roughly the same volume fish, onions and chopped potatoes, I generally take three of those plastic takeaway containers you get, fill one with finely chopped onions, one with diced potatoes, and the last one with the fish.<br>Heat a thick bottomed pan and put in a knob of butter, add the onions, potatoes and a small amount of chicken bouillon paste or stock cube (dry not mixed with water, this should be a SMALL amount, it is just to add a little depth to the final soup we are not making smoked haddock and chicken soup, although I did accidentally mix a batch of Cullen Skink with a batch of Chicken &amp; Sweetcorn soup and it was fucking delicious) and sweat them off till the onions are completely soft and the potatoes are starting to cook through (they should have started smushing up a bit around the edges). Season lightly, probably best to under season at this point just to be safe<br>Add half the fish and cover with just enough water to cover the ingredients, just enough, if you think it's enough it's probably slightly too much.<br>Let this simmer until the potatoes are cooked enough that they burst when pressed against the side of the pan with a wooden spoon.<br>Add the rest of the fish and a good slug of cream and bring back to heat, let it cook out for a little while and check the seasoning.<br><br>I also like to add cubed smoked bacon or pancetta when sweating the onions and potatoes, but not too much, and if you do this then it's not really Cullen Skink anymore.]]></description><link>starters\soups\cullen-skink.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Starters/Soups/Cullen Skink.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 18:04:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Haggis, Neep and Tattie Soup]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>Haggis
<br>Neeps
<br>Tatties
<br><br>This is a "leftover" soup. After a traditional meal of Haggis with mashed potato and mashed turnip, you may have a load of leftovers, through the whole lot in a pan and add some liquid (water will do as the haggis has enough flavour anyway), bring to the boil and using a whisk or stick blender combine all the ingredients until smooth. You won't be able to get it perfectly smooth because of the oats in the haggis but there should be no big lumps and the three ingredients should be completely combined.<br>Ideally the proportions of the three ingredients should be roughly equivalent to the portions you would serve for dinner. So, if you had three portions of haggis, you would use three portions of mash and three of neeps.<br>This soup doesn't look that appetising, but it is delicious.]]></description><link>starters\soups\haggis,-neeps-and-tatties-soup.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Starters/Soups/Haggis, Neeps and Tatties Soup.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 18:04:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Starters]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 ]]></description><link>starters\starters.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Starters/Starters.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 12:07:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[index]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><a data-href="Starters" href="\starters\starters.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Starters</a><br>
<a data-href="Lunches" href="\lunches\lunches.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Lunches</a><br>
<a data-href="Mains" href="\mains\mains.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Mains</a><br>
<a data-href="Puddings" href="\puddings\puddings.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Puddings</a><br>
<a data-href="Sides" href="\sides\sides.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Sides</a><br>
<a data-href="Snacks" href="\snacks\snacks.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Snacks</a><br>
<a data-href="Odds &amp; Sods" href="\odds-&amp;-sods\odds-&amp;-sods.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Odds &amp; Sods</a><br>
<a data-href="Components" href="\components\components.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Components</a>]]></description><link>index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">index.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 12:08:49 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>